<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Demo | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/category/demo/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/category/demo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Demo</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Demo</title>
      <link>https://example.com/category/demo/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>My week 23.05 - 29.05</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started-6-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started-6-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-week&#34;&gt;My week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happened this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.Studied English&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.Passed a big homework assignment in programming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.Celebrated a friend&amp;rsquo;s birthday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific programming languages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started-7-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started-7-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;scientific-programming-languages&#34;&gt;Scientific programming languages&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fortran&#34;&gt;Fortran&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortran is the language of the past in scientific computation, and one of the main languages of the present, as far as physics is concerned. Its main strengths at the moment are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a huge body of well-debugged and working code available;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a large base of experience residing in &amp;ldquo;older&amp;rdquo; physicists (pretty much all of us over the age of thirty?);&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last point is perhaps the most important, as Fortran has a &amp;ldquo;model&amp;rdquo; of the computer which is simple enough that one does not have to be a professional (i.e., extensive training or self-education in computer science or programming) to produce a reasonable Fortran program.
This is not to say that it is not possible to produce a bad Fortran program. It is quite easy, but that is true of pretty much every computer language to some degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortran 90 extends fortran in several useful ways, and makes it a more modern programming language, while retaining full compatibility with Fortran-77 code. Two of the more interesting features are aggregrate data types (&amp;ldquo;structures&amp;rdquo;) and built-in operations on arrays and matrices. In my opinion, Fortran tends to lose big as projects get more complex. The support for reuse and encapsulation of code is fairly poor in Fortran, at least in Fortran-77. Fortran 90 has more support for this, but I have little experience with it. Also, most graphical-interface and visualization packages have no native Fortran support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Fortran 90 proponents would like to see some of the &amp;ldquo;dangerous&amp;rdquo; elements of Fortran-77 removed from the language. I think this is a bad idea. Go here to read why I think so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;c-and-c&#34;&gt;C and C++&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C is an interesting choice as a scientific language. It is extremely flexible and available on about every machine known to man. Also, one of the best C compilers (gcc) is available for free. Almost all visualization and user-interface packages support the C language. C is frequently taught as a first or second language in university computer-science departments.
A long-standing gripe about C is that it produces slower code than does the equivalent Fortran. Nowadays, computer speeds are doubling every year or so, and C compilers don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be doing that bad compared to Fortran anymore (typical C code runs between 50 and 100% as fast as the equivalent Fortran, depending on the application). In light of this, I think it&amp;rsquo;s hard to discard C on the basis of the speed of the code it produces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a good scientific programming language. The C language is fairly close to the hardware, and it is quite easy to make big mistakes in coding an application. These mistakes often don&amp;rsquo;t display themselves in small test cases, since they involve memory-management issues and the like. Also, programming large applications in C requires some degree of professionalism, meaning a fairly deep grasp of the language. As such, it is a bad language for mainstream scientific programming; typically only the creator of a program, or people with real expertise in computer programming, will be able to understand a large C application unless it is very carefully written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe these comments also apply to C++ coding. The concerns about readability and professionalism apply perhaps even more strongly here than for &amp;ldquo;just C&amp;rdquo;. C++ has the advantage of being the most-popular object-oriented language, but it is also recognized as being a fairly cryptic one. Again, a certain degree of professionalism is necessary to program a C++ application which is understandable to others. Packages which automatically generate C++ code from user-specified pseudocode help alleviate the problem, but then we are faced with asking all users to use the same C++ generator, which is another problem of the same magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above two are the &amp;ldquo;traditional&amp;rdquo; choices. I now turn to newer languages which are less well known in the scientific community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;python&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python is an object-oriented, extensible, interpreted language. It runs on essentially all Unix systems, as well as on DOS/Windows platforms and on the Mac. It is free and comes with complete source code. It is very easy to begin using Python &amp;mdash; at a simple level, it resembles Basic and can be used interactively in the same way as Basic. However, it supports object methods and &amp;ldquo;scales&amp;rdquo; nicely. Scaling indicates the relative difficulty of writing small vs. large applications. The object facilities help and encourage one to write an application in small pieces. These small pieces can be put together to make the big program, and the small pieces can also be used in other applications.
Another advantage of Python is its extensibility. One can write an object library in C, C++, or native Python, which can then either be dynamically or statically linked with the main Python system and used in Python programs. One can use this to make a programmable application, such as a data-plotting package. One would add a package to the interpreter which contained commands to set up your plots and to actually plot the data. This Python+graphics interpreter can be given a different name, such as &amp;ldquo;pygraph&amp;rdquo;, and invoked as a command. The interpreter will process the graphics commands and perform them. However, at the same time you can use any other valid Python command as a command to this graphics program! Thus one graphics input file for this program could first compute the result and then manipulate and plot it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The leap from this to having Python+package systems such as data-analysis programs, or experiment-control programs, is fairly obvious. This can also solve to some extent the above-mentioned dilemma about the use of C++. A professional programmer can produce a well-defined library package with a well-defined interface in C++, and this can be included into the Python programs for use. As Python is quite readable in much the same was as is Fortran, a &amp;ldquo;normal person&amp;rdquo; (i.e. someone who is not a professional programmer) can use this library in his programs. Both the professionals, who want the power and efficiency of C or C++, as well as the group who must use the result and be able to read and understand the program, can be happy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report design</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started-5-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started-5-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;design&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the presence of its own requirements at each university, which can be found in the methodological literature of your university, there are standards for preparing a practice report:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total amount of work does not exceed 40 sheets of standard A4 format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice report is numbered on all pages (except for the title page and the appendix to the practice work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text of the work is printed in black type Times New Roman 12-14 pt. Between the lines set double or one and a half spacing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indent from the new line is 1.25 pt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each section has its own title. The new section starts on a new line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before starting to create a document, acceptable page indents are set: 30 mm on the left margin, 20 mm on the right margin, 20 mm indent above and below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When preparing a report on practice according to GOST, it is unacceptable to transfer words. However, many university departments allow word wrapping, so check this point with your department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you study at a technical university, you may need a frame for the report.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight markup language</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;lightweight-markup-language&#34;&gt;Lightweight markup language&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Languages ​​designed to easily and quickly add formatting to text data are called Lightweight markup languages. Features of such languages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimum of functions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A small set of supported tags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to learn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The source text in this language is read with the same ease as the finished document.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are used where a person has to prepare text in a regular text editor (blogs, forums, wikis), or where it is important that a user with a regular text editor can also read the text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some widely used lightweight markup languages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BBCode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;restructured text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Textile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wiki markup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various auto-documentation systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;markup&amp;rdquo; (as a result of the process of the same name, English markup) comes from the English phrase &amp;ldquo;marking up&amp;rdquo; (&amp;ldquo;marking (as a process)&amp;rdquo;, lit. &amp;ldquo;marking, marking&amp;rdquo;), taken from the traditional publishing practice of putting special conditional marks on margins and in the text of the manuscript or proofreading before sending it to print. Thus, &amp;ldquo;markup men&amp;rdquo; indicated the typeface, style and font size for each part of the text. Nowadays, text markup is handled by editors, proofreaders, graphic designers, and, of course, the authors themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;τεχ&#34;&gt;ΤΕΧ&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike ordinary word processors and computer layout systems built on the WYSIWYG principle, in TeX the user only sets the text and its structure, and TeX independently formats the document based on the template chosen by the user, replacing the designer and layout designer. Documents are typed in their own markup language in the form of regular ASCII files containing information about text formatting or displaying images. These files (usually with the extension &amp;ldquo;.tex&amp;rdquo;) are translated by a special program into &amp;ldquo;.dvi&amp;rdquo; (device independent) files, which can be displayed on the screen or printed. DVI files can be converted to PostScript, PDF, or other electronic format with special software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TeX core is a low-level markup language containing indentation and font change commands. Huge opportunities in TeX are provided by ready-made sets of macros and extensions. The most common extensions to standard TeX (sets of templates, styles, etc.) are LaTeX (pronounced &amp;ldquo;latex&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;latex&amp;rdquo;) and AMS-TeX. When using the LaTeX extension package, you can turn an overgrown article into a book by changing one word in the source file, inserting a table of contents with one command, and not thinking about numbering sections, theorems, figures. There are many packages for designing chemical formulas (for example, XyMTeX package), diagrams (xypic), creating presentations and business cards, and the like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;usage&#34;&gt;Usage&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TeX can be used for all kinds of text, from short writing to multi-volume books, and TeX was originally created for longer texts and scientific papers. Many large scientific publishers use it for typography or book typesetting. Both the formula set and the font point have special power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, it has become possible to use TeX to automatically create complex layouts for XML data. Differences in syntax between the two descriptor languages ​​can be overcome with &amp;ldquo;TeXML&amp;rdquo;. Thus, in the context of XML publishing, TeX can be considered as an alternative to XSL-FO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;fonts&#34;&gt;Fonts&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create fonts, together with TeX, the METAFONT system specially developed by D. Knuth is used, in which fonts are described by programs in a specialized Meta language. PostScript Type 1, TrueType, and OpenType vector fonts can also be used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gencode&#34;&gt;GenCode&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of ​​using markup languages ​​in computer word processing was most likely first publicized by William W. Tunnicliffe at a conference in 1967. He himself called his proposal &amp;ldquo;universal coding&amp;rdquo; (English &amp;ldquo;generic coding&amp;rdquo;). In the 1970s, Tunnicliffe led the development of the GenCode standard for the publishing industry and later became chairman of one of the International Organization for Standardization (ISO) committees that created SGML, the first descriptive markup language. Brian Reid (eng. Brian Reid (computer scientist)) in his dissertation, which he defended in 1980 at Carnegie Mellon University, developed the proposed concept into a practical implementation of descriptive markup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, IBM researcher Charles Goldfarb is now commonly referred to as the &amp;ldquo;father&amp;rdquo; of markup languages. The basic concept came to him in 1969 while working on a primitive document management system designed for law firms. In the same year, he took part in the creation of the IBM GML language, which was first introduced in 1973.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1975, Goldfarb moved from Cambridge, Massachusetts to Silicon Valley, where he became the developer of the IBM Almaden Research Center. There, in 1978, he convinced IBM management to use GML for commercial purposes as part of the company&amp;rsquo;s Document Composition Facility, after which GML was widely used in business for several years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1978, the first developments began, which eventually led to the creation of the SGML standard, based on GML and GenCode. Goldfarb himself later chaired the SGML committee, which was adopted by ISO as a standard in October 1986.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some early implementations of computer markup languages ​​can be found in UNIX typography utilities such as troff and nroff. They allow you to insert formatting commands into the text of a document to format it according to the requirements of the editor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The availability of WYSIWYG (what you see is what you get) publishing software has supplanted most of these languages ​​among general users, although serious publishing work still uses markup for specific non-visual structures. text, and WYSIWYG editors now most often save documents in formats based on markup languages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My week 02.05 - 08.05</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started-3-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started-3-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-week&#34;&gt;My week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week was the birthday of a dear friend of mine. Unfortunately, now I am not in my hometown, but this did not stop me from congratulating him and finding out how he is feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also this week there was a graduation concert at my art college. String and wind instruments performed. I watched the broadcast online and really enjoyed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/getting-started-3-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/1_hu84acd29b5bf10053071add82428710fa_540832_c5c95e27027789eaf4827746f8c7997c.webp 400w,
               /post/getting-started-3-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/1_hu84acd29b5bf10053071add82428710fa_540832_158d8a775fcad0417f6af1186a025a08.webp 760w,
               /post/getting-started-3-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/1_hu84acd29b5bf10053071add82428710fa_540832_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/post/getting-started-3-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/1_hu84acd29b5bf10053071add82428710fa_540832_c5c95e27027789eaf4827746f8c7997c.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;570&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My week 09.05 - 15.05</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started-%D0%B4%D1%80%D1%83%D0%B3%D0%B0%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-week&#34;&gt;My week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were several holidays this week.
One of them is Victory Day. This is a celebration of the victory of the Red Army and the Soviet people over Nazi Germany in the Great Patriotic War of 1941-1945. On this day, a parade was held on Red Square and a beautiful bright fireworks display was launched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My relatives came to me in Moscow and we visited many amazing places, for example, Tsaritsino Park, or the Claude Monet exhibition. Everyone really enjoyed it and we had a great time together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also learned a lot this week. We did a lot of laboratory work, improved our skills in c++, arduno.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My week 16.05 - 22.05</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started-4-%D1%8F-%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%BF%D0%B8%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-week&#34;&gt;My week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several things happened this week:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1.I took part in the English Olympiad and took 1st place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2.I studied lists and binary trees in C++.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3.We have done several labs on operating systems and IT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version control.Git</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;version-control&#34;&gt;Version control&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is “version control”? Version control is a system that records changes to a file or set of files over time so that you can recall specific versions later. For the examples in this book, you will use software source code as the files being version controlled, though in reality you can do this with nearly any type of file on a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a graphic or web designer and want to keep every version of an image or layout (which you would most certainly want to), a Version Control System (VCS) is a very wise thing to use. It allows you to revert selected files back to a previous state, revert the entire project back to a previous state, compare changes over time, see who last modified something that might be causing a problem, who introduced an issue and when, and more. Using a VCS also generally means that if you screw things up or lose files, you can easily recover. In addition, you get all this for very little overhead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local Version Control Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people’s version-control method of choice is to copy files into another directory (perhaps a time-stamped directory, if they’re clever). This appr&amp;mdash;
title: Version control.Git
subtitle: This chapter will be about getting started with Git. We will begin by explaining some background on version control tools, then move on to how to get Git running on your system and finally how to get it set up to start working with. At the end of this chapter you should understand why Git is around, why you should use it and you should be all set up to do so.oach is very common because it is so simple, but it is also incredibly error prone. It is easy to forget which directory you’re in and accidentally write to the wrong file or copy over files you don’t mean to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To deal with this issue, programmers long ago developed local VCSs that had a simple database that kept all the changes to files under revision control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local version control diagram&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most popular VCS tools was a system called RCS, which is still distributed with many computers today. RCS works by keeping patch sets (that is, the differences between files) in a special format on disk; it can then re-create what any file looked like at any point in time by adding up all the patches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Centralized Version Control Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next major issue that people encounter is that they need to collaborate with developers on other systems. To deal with this problem, Centralized Version Control Systems (CVCSs) were developed. These systems (such as CVS, Subversion, and Perforce) have a single server that contains all the versioned files, and a number of clients that check out files from that central place. For many years, this has been the standard for version control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Centralized version control diagram&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This setup offers many advantages, especially over local VCSs. For example, everyone knows to a certain degree what everyone else on the project is doing. Administrators have fine-grained control over who can do what, and it’s far easier to administer a CVCS than it is to deal with local databases on every client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this setup also has some serious downsides. The most obvious is the single point of failure that the centralized server represents. If that server goes down for an hour, then during that hour nobody can collaborate at all or save versioned changes to anything they’re working on. If the hard disk the central database is on becomes corrupted, and proper backups haven’t been kept, you lose absolutely everything — the entire history of the project except whatever single snapshots people happen to have on their local machines. Local VCSs suffer from this same problem — whenever you have the entire history of the project in a single place, you risk losing everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distributed Version Control Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where Distributed Version Control Systems (DVCSs) step in. In a DVCS (such as Git, Mercurial, Bazaar or Darcs), clients don’t just check out the latest snapshot of the files; rather, they fully mirror the repository, including its full history. Thus, if any server dies, and these systems were collaborating via that server, any of the client repositories can be copied back up to the server to restore it. Every clone is really a full backup of all the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;6&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distributed version control diagram&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, many of these systems deal pretty well with having several remote repositories they can work with, so you can collaborate with different groups of people in different ways simultaneously within the same project. This allows you to set up several types of workflows that aren’t possible in centralized systems, such as hierarchical models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
